# DAMILOLA IBIKUNLE

# SENIOR SCIENTIFIC OFFICER

I am a senior scientific officer with 5 years of working experience in research and development within the areas of space and satellite technologies.

I also have over 3 years of professional experience in customer care service and a graduate educational background in Information Security.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### SENIOR SCIENTIFIC OFFICER

National Space Research and Development Agency (NASRDA)

Jan 2023 - Present

- Responsible for overseeing and managing the instrumentation team within the spacecraft aerodynamics and control department
- Ensuring accurate and adequate measurement and application of all data/apparatus used for a successful satellite design and mission life.
- Member of the team assigned to design and develop customizable Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) tailored for specific purposes.
- Conduct independent research on Space and Satellite Technologies.
- Active member of the Training and Technical Committee within the Nigerian Institute of Space Engineers (NISEng).

# **SCIENTIFIC OFFICER**

National Space Research and Development Agency (NASRDA)

Aug 2018 - Dec 2022.

- Conduct independent and extensive research on control systems for Space and Satellite Technologies.
- Member of the embedded systems team responsible for designing and developing space equipment, including Unmanned Ground Vehicles (UGVs) and Deep Space Antenna Trackers.

#### **CUSTOMER CARE REPRESENTATIVE**

Globacom Limited (GLO) Jan 2015 - July 2018

- Providing customers with accurate information about the company's products and services in response to their inquiries.
- Addressing and resolving customer account issues, and escalating them to the relevant channels when required.
- Efficiently updating and maintaining customer account information using a variety of company applications while exhibiting strong multitasking abilities.
- Creating service requests for each customer to facilitate the preparation of comprehensive product and services reports for company analysis.
- Assisting in sales efforts by advising and educating customers about new products and services introduced by the company.

# INTERNSHIP - NATIONAL YOUTH SERVICE CORPS (NYSC)

SHELL PETROLEUM DEVELOPMENT COMPANY OF NIGERIA - (SPDC ABUJA)
Jul 2011 - Jul 2012

- Offering infrastructure and IT support services.
- Managing and organizing records and manifests for visiting staff and guests.
- Assisting the welfare committee with various company events, including the annual Shell University Scholarship Scheme in Abuja.

### **EDUCATION**

#### MASTER OF SCIENCE (M.SC)

Information Security
University of Salford Manchester | Oct 2012 - Dec 2013

# **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.SC)**

**Computer Science** 

University of Lagos Akoka | Sept 2006 - Dec 2010

#### SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Python for Machine Learning and Deep Learning
- Microsoft Excel
- HTML/CSS
- Java script

#### OTHER SKILLS

- Research Skills
- Data Analysis
- Data Visualization
- Data Security
- Customer Relationship management
- Project Management
- Risk Assessment

#### CERTIFICATIONS

#### IBM DATA SCIENCE PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

IBM Skills Network

Jun 27, 2023

# CONTACT



https://damiieibikun.github.io/



https://github.com/Damiieibikun

 $\bowtie$ 

damiieibikun@gmail.com

7

+2349082069368



Abuja Nigeria